all of you underestimate life insurance
but it
is one of the most important things in our life
and today in this video we will learn
why should I get life insurance, which one should I get,
when, how much and how should I get it done.
At the end of this video you will
know very well which life
insurance you should get and which one you should not get
because if you have taken it without complete information
then it will cause you
harm instead of benefit throughout your life. It will
not change your life from India South
but it has so much power that it prevents the
left end of your family from changing even in bad times.
What does it mean after all?
It means that if you have taken insurance
then no one will know
when you have taken it.
You will continue with your normal work,
this will not make any change in your life.
But if you do not have life insurance
and God forbid something happens to you then
not only your family's life but your entire
lifestyle will change. Then it is possible that your
children will not be able to continue their studies in the same school.
Your family may
not be able to do everything properly to do this.
An amount is needed, so
remember, an insurance is like a boat that is
n't needed until a flood occurs.
You don't wait for the flood. But to ensure that it
comes in handy during a flood every year,
you have to pay a fixed amount. This is the
insurance premium.
My father's definition says that insurance
is an agreement between a person and an insurance company that
promises to provide a fixed amount to their future.
First, let's discuss whether we should buy an insurance
plan. There's no doubt
that death is an emotional toll that is
bound to take on a family member after someone's death,
regardless of their age.
Similarly, care promises to a family are
not only a burden, but
if the person who passed away was a breadwinner, there's a
monitoring mechanism that is
most painful.
If there were something like a time machine, you would
find that if those who have left this world were to come back, the
first thing they would do is buy insurance for themselves. This is
because their families had to face significant financial hardships after their death.  The
pain is perhaps reduced a little
and they are able to fulfill their incomplete responsibilities. So,
we have understood
why one should take life insurance,
so let us now understand whether one should take this life insurance in a mixed form.
In India, we get three ways of getting interest:
endowment from any plan and term
plan.
In endowment plan, you contact the company and decide the amount of insurance, that is, the amount for which
you are insured and whether the term will last or not.
You decide the
premium amount on the basis of 100%.
In this insurance plan, if the policy holder dies during the period you have decided, then a
notification is received and
if the policy holder survives till the end of the term, then he gets
both the deposited amount and the sum assured. This is an
endowment plan of the electronic kind. The
only difference in this is that the money
deposited is invested in the stock market,
from which whatever return is received is
passed on to the customer.
In simple language,
whatever is the value of the Chamber Road Plus Fund, on loading, the
family gets it.
Both endowment and
non-endowment plans offer both insurance and investment,
but the term plan only provides an
inference; there's no
investment or return.
Upon the policyholder's death,
you're simply left with a lump sum.
Term insurance has become very popular in recent years.
It's considered very cheap and a very
good insurance.
You can get a cover of 1 crore for just a few thousand rupees. However, if you
buy term insurance, your premium will run into lakhs.
Therefore, whenever you buy term insurance,
buy only term insurance and
invest the remaining money elsewhere.
You should separate the two, and you'll
get the benefits of both. The 1 crore plan says
you shouldn't mix term insurance with investment.
Now the question arises: should you
buy it?
Someone rightly said that insurance is
like a parachute. If you have it,
you'll be saved, and if you don't, you wo
n't get a second chance. This means
you should take timely decisions.
But should everyone buy term insurance? No,
only those who have
any kind of financial burden should take it.  Let's
assume that someone with a
wife and children in their family, along with a car
and a home loan,
needs insurance first. Even if your net worth is
fifty times your annual income, you do
n't need insurance.
Another
important thing about insurance is that when
prayer doesn't work, but Suresh does
his job. This is a big deal.
Prayer is placed above the doctor,
but when both are not useful,
insurance comes in as a guarantee.
How much insurance should you take? Now let's
understand how much insurance you should take. The idea is
simple:
after the breadwinner's death, all the responsibilities should be
fulfilled. That's all. Whether the insurance is off or
not, the insurance should be worth 15 times your annual income.
After this,
you should also add all the types of loans you have to it. You go to manage internet service.
Next, to
get tax exemption, there
is a small insurance product, but people often take those products to
save income tax. This is
a wrong approach. After this, it has
also been seen in people that  It has been reported that his annual
income is ₹1000000, but
he has taken insurance for only 5 lakhs. This mistake
happens because he takes an
endowment or ULIP plan instead of term insurance.
All these mistakes are to be
avoided.
Today we will discuss what are the
things that you should
keep in mind while getting insurance. The
most important thing about it is
that you are the one who is getting insurance, but it is not for you,
it is for your family. You should first be clear about
how much insurance you want to take. There will be
no change in this time after getting the position.
Insurance should be taken and should be taken only as long as
you have income or
responsibilities. If someone's source of
income is salary, then he should take insurance till the age of 60 years.
But if his
responsibilities end in 60 years, then
he should extend his term till 60 years.
While filling the form, there are
also questions related to the Prominence Insurance policy. You should
read them carefully and answer them correctly.
No wrong answer should be given to any question. This was taken
yesterday after giving information.  It is
equivalent to taking inspirational.
Double cross all the things like nominee mobile number email id address
and all these should be filled correctly in the form.
After polishing, when you ask, you
receive the comment. From that day onwards,
within the next 15 days, if you do not like any of the possible
features and for some reason you
want to stop flaxseed, then you can do it
but after the 16th day, I
give you the right to stop Tulsi. After
understanding all these things, you should
choose a better insurance for yourself.
In the end, someone has rightly said that there are
things worse than death in this world. To know that,
know the house where death has occurred and it should be
international. Thank you to